# James Symons-Hicks

≥ j.symons-hicks@lse.ac.uk in LinkedIn

#### **Profile**

I am a Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant at the LSE Centre for Macroeconomics, focusing on Fiscal Policy, Productivity & Growth, and Family Macroeconomics. I have also worked as a research assistant at University College London with a focus on financial decision-making and experimental economics. My research interests include macroeconomics, financial economics, behavioural economics, and experimental economics.

#### Education

## University College London $MSc\ Economics$

 $\mathbf{Sep}\ \mathbf{2023} - \mathbf{Sep}\ \mathbf{2024}$ 

Grade: Pending

Core Modules: Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Econometrics, Research Methods, Dissertation.

Optional Modules: Advanced Macroeconomic Theory, Advanced Microeconometrics, Machine Learning in Economics, Topics in Money and Finance.

Modules Audited: Advanced Microeconomic Theory.

#### University College London BSc Economics

Sep 2020 – Jun 2023

Grade: First Class Honours

Selected Coursework: Microeconomics (76%), Economics of Finance (78%), Advanced Economics of Finance (72%), Spanish L6 (76%), Macroeconomic Theory & Policy (72%).

Dissertation: "Unravelling the Influence of Retail Investors on Liquidity and Volatility in UK Markets" (74%)

#### St. David's Sixth Form College, Cardiff

Sep 2018 – Jul 2020 *Grade*: A\*A\*A\*

A-Levels - Economics, Mathematics, Spanish, Media Studies.

Awards: Academic Excellence - Economics & Media Studies. Outstanding Studentship - Spanish.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: English (Native), Spanish (Advanced).

Programming: Proficient - Stata, MATLAB, Python, IATEX. Familiar - R, Mathematica.

Other: Microsoft Excel (proficient), Level 3 Emergency First Aid at Work, LTA Level 2 Tennis Coach.

### **Academic Positions**

#### Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant

September 2024 - Present

Centre for Macroeconomics, London School of Economics

London, UK

• Working with Prof. Matthias Doepke and Dr. Ethan Ilzetzki.

## Research Assistant

 $May\ 2022-September\ 2024$ 

## Prof. Antonio Guarino, University College London

London, UK

- Working across multiple projects relating to financial decision-making and experimental economics.
- Assisted with interactive, computer-based laboratory experiments of undergraduate students and professional traders.
- Developed MATLAB programmes to analyse experimental data using Maximum Likelihood Estimation.
- Utilised Python to clean experimental data, create graphics, and conduct hypothesis testing.
- Editing and proofreading academic articles for publication.
- Creating and editing conference presentation slides, including creating graphics and visuals.

#### Research & Publications

#### The Influence of Market Dynamics on Retail Investor Attention | Link

Oct 2023

• Published in UCL Journal of Economics 2023.

## Impacts of the EU Referendum Decision on the Welsh Economy | Link

Jun 2022

• Shortlisted for UCL's Explore Econ Conference 2022.

## Economics with Humans: The Importance of Behavioural Economics | Link

Jan 2022

• Blog article for The Economic Tribune.

## Other Research Experience

Peer Reviewer, UCL Journal of Economics	2024
Student Research Fellow, UCL Economic Tribune	Oct 2022 – Jul 2023
Presenter & Panel Discussion Member, Discover Economics Project	June 2023
Scientific Committee, UCL Explore Econ Conference	June 2023

## Other Work Experience

## The Access to Sport Project $Tennis\ Coach$

Nov~2021-Aug~2022

London, UK

- Delivered free/low-cost tennis sessions to children and adults, including 30+ players school groups and summer holiday camps.
- Supported 5 volunteers/junior coaches in qualification progressions by providing on-court feedback during lessons.
- Undertook additional training sessions to teach players with additional learning needs.

### Extra-Curricular

Captain of UCL Tennis Men's 3, Member of UCL Economist's Society, Member of UCL Snowsports.